(ゼツ)裏切り者の虫ケラが
やっと死んだか。
The vermin traitor has finally died, eh?
(ゼツ)虫ケラは 虫ケラでも
このしつこさは ゴキブリだったな。
He was vermin…
and persistent as a cockroach.
ハハハハハ！
(ナルト)オビトを笑うな。
Don't laugh at Obito!
(サクラ)ナルト…。
Naruto…
ナルト… お前も
これ以上 刃向かってると→
Naruto…
If you keep resisting,
you'll end up pitifully crumbling
to ash just like him!
崩れて灰になった
哀れでみじめなそいつと→
同じになるんだ。
火影になろうとしたオビトは
俺には…。
As someone who tried to
become Hokage,
Obito is…
なっ！
かっこよくしか見えねえよ！
…nothing but awesome to me!
No way!
バカな！
《くっ！ 動けん》
I can't move!
《カカシ : たいした力もないくせに
また 残されたということか》
I don't even have
much strength left,
and yet, I was left behind again?
((オビト : 大丈夫か？ リン… カカシ…。
Are you all right, Rin?
Kakashi?
(カカシ)オビト！
Obito!
(オビト)やめろ。 いいんだ カカシ。
Don't…
It's okay, Kakashi.
俺は もう ダメみたいだ。
I don't think I can make it…
体の右側は
ほとんど潰れちまって→
My right side is totally crushed.
感覚すら ねえ…。
I can't even feel anything…
(カカシ)クソ！
Damn it!
この俺の写輪眼をやるからよ。
I'm giving you my Sharingan.
里のやつらが なんて言おうと
お前は 立派な上忍だ。
Whatever the village may say…
you are…a great jonin.
それが 俺の気持だ。
That's how I really feel…
(受け取ってくれ))
So please accept it.
((リン : カカシ…))
Kakashi…
((リン！
リン！
– Rin!
《オビト : キミは また…》
Again, you…
《ありがとう リン。
Thank you, Rin.
俺も オビトも
そろそろ そっちへ行くよ。
Obito and I will be
joining you shortly.
また ３人で
ゆっくり話をしよう》
We can catch up then,
the three of us together…
《リン… 今度は あの世で→
Rin…
This time, let's…
少し 俺と
２人きりの時間を過ごそう》
spend some alone time together.
Just you and me…
《カカシは邪魔だ。
ここに置いていくよ》
Kakashi would just be in the way.
I'll leave him here.
これは… 神威!?
This is…Kamui!
オビト… お前！
Obito! You!
カカシ… お前は 当分 こっちにいろ。
Kakashi…
you stay here a little while longer.
(すぐに来んじゃねえぞ))
Don't you rush to follow us!
《なぜだ!? オビト！
Why, Obito?
俺は なんのために…》
What am I even here for?
THE SHARINGAN REVIVED
ヘヘ まいったよな。
This is embarrassing…
Screwing up like that in front of you.
いきなり かっこ悪いとこ
見せちまって。
少しは落ち着いたみたいだね。
It looks like
you've calmed down a bit.
さぁ オビト。
Okay, Obito.
リン もう少しだけ
待ってくれないか？
Rin, do you mind waiting
just a bit longer?
オビト？
Obito?
あの世にいく間
ほんの少しでいい→
Only a little bit before
we move on…
もう少し遠回りしていきたいんだ。
I'd like to make one more
detour along the way.
もう 今度は誰を助けたいの？
Who do you want to save this time?
カカシだ。
Kakashi.
やっと リンと
２人きりになれたんだ。
I've finally gotten alone time with you.
すぐ あいつに
来られちゃ台なしだ。
It'll be wasted if he ends up
coming here right away.
それに あいつが何もできないで
はたけに突っ立ってる→
Besides… He's out there helpless.
Just like his namesake, he's a scarecrow
in the middle of a garden…
文字どおりの
カカシみたいになってるのは→
何か シャクなんだ。
And I'm sort of annoyed by it.
フフフ いろいろあったけど→
Despite all that's happened,
you two are still close, huh?
やっぱり仲がいいんだね。
N-No way!
そ そんなことねえよ
あいつと俺は水と油だ。
We're oil and water!
フフ それで すぐにいけるの？
So?
You can go just like that?
ああ チャクラってのは→
Yeah…
Chakra is an energy
that connects two worlds.
２つの世界をつなげる力だ。
カカシに会ってくるよ。
I'm gonna go see Kakashi!
ここで待ってる。
I'll be waiting right here.
悪いな リン すぐ戻ってくっからな。
Sorry, Rin!
I'll be right back!
Obito?!
(カカシ)オビト!?
あの世にいく前に
お前がこっちに来ないよう→
Before I go to the next world,
I thought I'd emphasize to you…
to not to come
running after me so quickly.
念押ししておこうと思ってよ。
せっかく上忍祝いのプレゼントで
この目をやったのに→
Besides, it's going to
keep bothering me
if this eye I gave you to
celebrate your promotion to jonin,
それが帰ってきたんじゃ
寝覚めが悪くてよ。
came back to me.
オビト お前…。
Obito, you…
つっても もうこの世で
目覚めることもないんだが。
Then again, it's not like I'll be
springing back to life anymore.
そんなことより
俺は さっき ナルトに→
More importantly,
you know how I told Naruto
to become Hokage?
火影になれっつったんだけどよ。
ただ そりゃ 七代目だ。
I meant to say as the Seventh.
六代目火影は お前がなれ カカシ。
You be the Sixth Hokage, Kakashi.
まだ就任したわけじゃないが
祝いのプレゼントを先にやっとくよ。
I know you haven't taken office yet,
but I'm giving you your gift now.
期限付きだが
役に立たないものじゃない。
It has a fixed time limit,
but it isn't useless.
わかってるよな？
Do you get what I'm saying?
そもそも他国にまで
とどろかせた自分の勇名を→
I mean…you haven't forgotten
your famous nickname
that's known throughout
the lands, have you?
忘れちゃいないだろ？
(オビト)写輪眼のカカシって名を。
That name, Kakashi of the Sharingan!
(サスケ)ハァッ！
《いくぞ みんな！》
Let's do this, guys!
(守鶴)フン。
Mmhm.
(又旅)はい。
Yes!
(磯撫)うん。
Yup!
(孫悟空)よっしゃ。
All right!
(穆王)了解。
Roger.
(犀犬)あいよ。
Sure thing!
Gotcha!
(重明)わかった。
(牛鬼)おう。
Yeah!
(九喇嘛)やるぞ。
Here we go!
仙法 超尾獣螺旋手裏剣！
Sage Art: Super Tailed Beast
Rasen-Shuriken!
そりゃ～！
ナイス ナルト！
Nice, Naruto!
There's no way they can
come out of that unscathed.
《あれをくらったら さすがに
無傷じゃいられないはず》
ううっ！
う～！
《まさか 母さん ここで!?》
Oh no! Don't tell me Mother's—!
なんなの？
What's that?
また… デケエのに なんだ？
She turned into
another gigantic thing?
What is that?
狼？ 狸？ ムジナ？
A wolf? Tanuki?
Badger? Or a rabbit?
うさぎか？
なんでもいい。
It doesn't matter.
Now it's easier to get close.
これで近づきやすくなった
封印もしやすくなる！
And it'll be easier to seal her!
《これは人型じゃない。
It's not…humanoid?
母さんの意思で
十尾化したんじゃないぞ。
Mother didn't transform into
Ten Tails of her own will.
さっきのナルトの攻撃に
尾獣どもが呼応して→
Are the Tailed Beasts
within her resonating
in response to Naruto's attack
and starting to split apart?
分離しかかって
いるんじゃないのか？
安定していない！》
They're not stable!
ギャー！
サスケ あの白い手に つかまんな。
Sasuke, don't get grabbed
by that white hand!
一瞬で取り込まれちまうぞ。
It will absorb you instantly!
しかも速え！
わかってる！
And it's fast too!
I know that!
ああ！
サスケ お前の瞳術で
サクラちゃんを！
Sasuke!
Protect Sakura with
your Visual Prowess!
All right, way to go!
よっしゃ やったぜ！
須佐能乎 誰だ？
A Susano'o?! Whose was it?
って ええ？
お前じゃねえのかよ！
W-What? That wasn't you?!
《クッ どういうことだ？》
What's going on?!
(サクラ)カカシ先生？
Kakashi Sensei!
《オビト ありがとう》
Thank you…Obito.
バカな そんなはずが…。
That's impossible. No way!
Sure it is!
おかしかねえだろ。
We are talking about the Copy Ninja,
Kakashi of the Sharingan!
コピー忍者 写輪眼のカカシ
っていうぐらいだからな。
先生ってば！
もう 写輪眼は
持っていないはずだが。
But he shouldn't have
the Sharingan anymore…
よくわからないけど
助かった。
I don't get it, but he saved me!
You watch along with me.
《お前も一緒に見ていてくれ。
今度こそ あいつらを
世界を守る！》
This time, I'll protect them…
and the world!
Here it comes!
来たぞ！
うわ！
How about this?
《これならどうだ！
神威の力を 手裏剣に！》
Combining the power
of the Kamui into…
shuriken!
Kamui Shuriken!
神威手裏剣！
Just as I thought…
思ったとおりだ。
Gaining Six Path's power enhances
one's Visual Prowess too!
六道の力を得ていたぶん
瞳力が上がっている。
《この力 オビトの写輪眼？
それが なんでカカシ先生に？》
This power…
It's Obito's Sharingan?
But why does
Kakashi Sensei have it?
おお サスケのより すげえ！
Wow!
That's more amazing
than yours, Sasuke!
《このチャクラは…》
This chakra is—!
(ゼツ)無限月読の忍たちから
チャクラを直接抽出できる→
This Root Time-Space is
Mother's exclusive domain,
where she can
directly extract chakra
この始球空間こそ
母さんの特別領域。
from shinobi trapped in
the Infinite Tsukuyomi!
尾獣どもは すでに安定し→
The Tailed Beasts are now stable,
and Mother has even produced
a Truthseeker Orb…
更には
母さんの求道玉まで出した。
An Expansive Kekkei Moura
Truthseeker Orb
風火土雷水 陰陽
すべての性質を合わせた→
that contains
each and every nature…
血継網羅の膨張求道玉。
Wind, fire, earth, lightning,
water, shadow, and light.
It is the beginning of
a new Time-Space.
新たな空間の始まりだ。
And you all will
become its sacrifice!
お前らは その犠牲となるのだ。
こりゃ… 俺の後ろのと同じ玉だ。
That thing!
It's the same sphere
as the one behind me!
The difference in size is too drastic!
大きさが違いすぎるだろ。
And it's growing rapidly!
それに
どんどん大きくなってるぞ。
(カカシ)さすがに
あれほど大きなものを→
I definitely can't teleport away such
a gigantic object with the Kamui.
神威で飛ばせない。
俺たちが時空間に飛んで
いったん逃げたとしても→
Even if we get out of this Time-Space
and escape temporarily…
あれが大きくなりすぎれば
当然 もう戻ってこられなくなる。
If that thing becomes too big,
we won't be able to return here.
あれを止めるには…。
In order to stop that…
We need to seal
that Rabbit Granny away right now!
本体のうさぎババアを 今すぐ
封印するしかねえってことだ。
だよね。
集まれ 作戦を伝える。
You're right.
Gather 'round. I've got a plan.
これが俺たち 元第７班としての
最後の任務だ。
This will be our last mission
as the former Squad 7!
俺たちで世界を救うぞ。
フン。
We're going to save the world!
Yeah!
おう！
了解！
Roger!
(カグヤ)わらわは不死。
I am immortal.
どちらか一方が死ねば
封印はできぬ。
If either of you die,
you cannot seal me away.
さて…。
Now then...
Which shall it be?
どちらにする？
俺が相手だ この野郎！
You're mine, damn it!
いや 一緒に攻める。
No, we attack her together.
やつは封印を恐れ
注意力が二分される。
She's scared of being sealed
and her attention will be divided!
途中まで連れていけ あとは跳ぶ。
おう。
Take me part of the way.
Then I'll fly the rest of the way.
Right!
《速い！》
So fast!
《母さんは力を得たばかり。
Mother just gained more power.
Both her power and speed
are now exponentially greater!
威力もスピードも
段違いになってんのさ》
《やはり… いい能力だな オビト。
Being able to pass through things,
really is a handy ability, Obito…
すり抜けるのは…。
そして この技も復活だ》
And now, I can resurrect this move too!
《神威雷切！》
Kamui Lightning Blade!
くっ！
母さん！
Mother!
《ゼツ : まずい 右手が…》
This is bad!
Her right arm!
《別空間の中へ逃げるにも
空間を広げる時間がない。
There's not enough time to escape
into another Time-Space!
なら！》
Then!
ぐぁっ！
《やはり どちらもアシュラの転生者。
So they were both
Ashura's reincarnates, after all.
あのとき すでに変化していたか。
They must have,
switched back then.
そして… 右が本物！》
So then, the one on the right
is the real one!
Kamui!
神威！
《まずい…》
Not good.
《氷の空間へ。
I'll go to the Ice World…
No…
いや インドラの転生者には天照が…。
The Indra reincarnate
possesses the Amaterasu…
That wouldn't be good!
それは ダメだ！》
Don't forget about me!
We're both women…
《私だっているんだ。
同じ女なら バカにしないで！》
so don't mock me!
なっ…。
《ナルト サスケ サクラ…》
Naruto…Sasuke…Sakura!
((ニシシッ。
《カカシ : ベタなイタズラか。
A silly prank…
だが イタズラもチームワークがあるなら…》
Still, if this prank
was the result of teamwork…
ハハハハハッ！
引っかかった 引っかかった。
He fell for it!
《カカシ : 仕掛けたのは ナルト》
So Naruto's the perp.
先生 ごめんなさい。
私は とめたんですが ナルト君が。
I'm so sorry, Sensei.
I tried to stop him, but Naruto…
《カカシ : サクラは言い訳 自身の保身。
Sakura makes excuses
and tries to protect herself.
サスケは我関せず。
仲間とすら思っていないようだな。
Sasuke minds his own business.
He probably doesn't
consider them comrades.
チームワークのカケラもなしか…》
There's not
a shred of teamwork…
(カカシ)ん～ なんて言うのかな。
How do I put this…
My first impression of you guys
is not good!
お前らの第一印象は 嫌いだ。
俺さ 俺さ 名前は うずまきナルト。
I'll go! I'll go!
I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
I love instant ramen.
好きなものは カップラーメン。
もっと好きなもんは
イルカ先生におごってもらった→
But I love the ramen at Ichiraku that
Iruka Sensei treats me to even more!
一楽のラーメン！
嫌いなものは
お湯をいれてからの３分間。
And I hate having to wait three minutes
after pouring in the hot water.
将来の夢は… 火影を超す！
My future dream is…
to surpass the Hokage!
んでもって 里のやつら全員に
俺の存在を認めさせてやるんだ。
名は うちはサスケ。
嫌いなものなら たくさんあるが
好きなものは別にない。
それから 夢なんて言葉で
終わらす気はないが→
野望はある。
一族の復興と
ある男を必ず… 殺すことだ。
私は 春野サクラ。
好きなものは… ってゆ～か！
好きな人は… え～と…。
将来の夢も言っちゃおうかな。
キャーッ！
どいつもこいつも 見事にバラバラ。
チームワークとは 程遠いな。
俺らも似たようなものだったが。
(まぁ やるだけやってみるさ))
《うん いい画だ。
今のお前らは…》
今だ！
しゃ～んなろ～！
よっしゃ！
(カカシ)大好きだ。